# Sunil Kumar

sunilkumarsheoran@gmail.com +1-6043674432 linkedin.com/in/sunilkumarsheoran ECS 412, University of Victoria,

Victoria, BC, Canada. V8P 5C2

I am a Master of Computer Science student at the University of Victoria. I have 3 years of software development experience with software product companies including Drishti-Soft Solutions aka Ameyo and Zillious Solutions. Seeking co-op opportunities where I can fully utilize my skills for the success of the organization and learn new skills for the cutting edge of technologies in the industry.

## **Education**

## M.Sc. in Computer Science

Jan 2019 – Expected Jan 2021

University of Victoria – 7.33 / 9.0 GPA

Projects: Training a DQN agent for Coinrun (GitHub) and Matchmaking for online multiplayer games (GitHub).

# B.Tech. in Information Technology Aug 2010-May 2014

NIT Durgapur - 8.10 / 10.0 CGPA

K V Bengdubi - 85.8 % & 79.8 % Projects: Book Shop Management, Tic Tac Toe bot

Projects: Collage Study Point Website (GitHub), Digital Clock on Multisim and Exploration bot.

#### 12th & 10th CBSE

March 2007 & March 2010

## **Technical Skills**

- Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, Golang, PostgreSQL, MySQL, C, C++, PHP, CSS, HTML, Shell.
- Tools: Docker, Kubernetes, Google Cloud Platform, Office, Adobe Photoshop, gRPC, Swagger, REST APIs, Git, GWT, JDBC, Hibernate, Eclipse, PyCharm, OOPs, Data Structures, Deep Learning, Electron, Angular, Slack, Eclipse Modeling Framework, Jasper Report, uxpin.
- **Operating Systems**: Linux, Windows

## **Experience**

#### Technical Associate / Zillious Solutions, New Delhi, India.

July 2018 - Dec 2018

- Implemented a solution for a long-standing issue (java enum limit) requiring minimum changes in the application.
- Design and developed support for customizable voucher and integrated multiple payment gateways.
- Integrated pre-developed machine learning model into the application for finding duplicate hotels.

## Software Developer / Drishti-Soft Solutions, Gurugram, India.

June 2014 - Sep 2016

- Majorly worked on Ameyo Report (GWT based front-end and Jasper based backend) this includes UI Renew, transformer (denormalize data for reporting) modeling to ease the generation of new transformers and backend enhancements.
- Created a Report Scheduler (Quartz library) with support for Centralized Reporting (Ameyo ART) and Graphical Reports.
- Increased performance for a large customer's database (PostgreSQL) by 80-90% using table partition and Multicolumn Indexes.
- Increased the Stats Manager's performance by 60% using cache (SoftHashMap) for reflective calls.
- Developed a context-aware Report Designer: Front-end GWT UI filled with generated data based on Model instances (.xmi) and output from the UI is a Model (EMF) object (.drxml) which converted by backend into a jasper-based object (.jrxml).
- Created Magic Numbers: Predicts hardware requirements (CPU, RAM, and HDD) based on customer requirements.
- Automate HDFC collection process. Fresh UI, Integrating HCP for storage, SSO Authenticating server & Centralized Exclusion.
- Awarded with Excellence Award 2016 and won /tmp 2014 (10 days 24x7 coding event).
- Part of the Hiring team for the 2016 and 2017 batches. (Question preparation, Interview Rounds and training after hiring).

## Software Developer Intern / Morphing Machines, Bangalore, India.

June 2013 - Aug 2013

Designed and developed the front-end interface for a research project called 'Development of A Flexible Framework for A Network On Chip'. We wrote a research paper about it (GitHub).

## **Hobbies**

- Video Games (2nd in COBX and Aorus Land 2017 National DOTA 2 tournament, Won Playtonia & Indian LAN Gaming Cup)
- Karate (Green belt Shūkōkai Karate)
- Solving Programming Problems (1st place in behind the Scene and InCanity in MuKTi '13 and 2nd place in Simplex in ANK '12)
- Playing Chess (3<sup>rd</sup>, 1<sup>st</sup> and 2<sup>nd</sup> position in Regional Sports meet in 2007,2006 and 2005. Hence went to Nationals 3 times)

## References

- Sahil Gandhi (sahilgandhi2011@gmail.com) Product Evangelist, Drishti-Soft Solutions aka Ameyo.
- Dr. Hausi Müller (hausi@uvic.ca) Professor, University of Victoria.